I just had to put my mom into a
different home. It's actually kind of
cool. It's sad, but she's been falling.
And they have this like like new AI orb
that sits up there and it kind of does
like a kind of radar type situation.
>> Mhm.
>> And it detects falls.
>> Oh, wow.
>> So, the second she falls in the home,
like they can rush in and like help her
out and all of that. And they they
carpet the hell out of it now and stuff
like that. So.
>> you think about sort of pre-grieving
that or contending with that yourself?
>> In terms of
>> With family, that's rough. I mean
>> Yeah, I mean
>> It doesn't sound easy. So, if you were
like play forward the tape, right? It's
like I mean I think about this with my
own parents and it's just like nobody
nobody lasts forever.
>> It's one of those things where it's so
funny cuz when you're a teenager and I
remember when my dad was having a hard
time standing and this was like when I
was much younger before he passed and I
was like, "Oh, dad's going to be on like
the thing that I might have to like push
him on it if he has to sit down." Kind
of those walkers that can also be
something you can push somebody on. I
was so embarrassed, you know? I was
like, "Oh, other people are looking at
us or whatever." And now I like push my
mom with pride in her walker thing and
I'm like
>> I don't know.
>> You don't know when it's going to what's
going to happen, but the only thing you
can do is just make sure to show up, you
know, and hang out.
>> Yeah.
>> And and I'm very lucky that
my mom has dementia, but it's it is a
type that
it's not Alzheimer's, so it's probably
vascular or something.
>> Yeah.
>> So, I can walk in and she knows who I
am. She can't tell you what she had for
breakfast, but she knows who I am, which
is like
>> Yeah.
>> I'll take that all day long.
>> For sure.
>> You know, so
>> Yeah. I know you have family members
that are in the same boat, which is
freaking tough.
>> I have a ton of family members with
Alzheimer's. I mean, literally got a
call from one of my relatives wanting to
discuss interventions and
it's a tough conversation because there
really isn't much. Like you have to
as far as I can tell, act preemptively,
which is why actually this relates to
another bullet of mine. You have five?
>> What was that?
>> How many bullets did you have?
>> Oh.
How many [laughter] bullets you have?
>> I was just curious.
>> Of all of all the rye whiskeys, it's the
only one that I can tolerate. I loathe
stationary bikes. I just I I really find
stationary biking to be one of the most
soul-crushing things in the world.
>> It's the worst.
>> However,
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, I've tried Peloton and didn't
like their ergonomics and so on for a
bunch of reasons.
And then I have tried very expensive
very very expensive setups recommended
to me by fancy doctors and so on, which
are just like too uncomfortable. Like
I'm incredibly hunched over. Like my
back is basically parallel with the
floor.
>> Dude, what are you talking about?
>> like kneeing myself in the stomach. It's
so uncomfortable.
>> machines? What are you talking
>> I'm talking about getting on like a
stationary bike, but if you're like in a
racing position, you have to adopt this
hunchback. And like there are a million
reasons why I find that uncomfortable.
There is a bike, however,
it's very easy to find. It's pretty
common in public gyms, called the Keiser
M3i Studio Indoor Bike. I don't know why
they have to make it so difficult in its
nomenclature, but the Keiser M3i is
unique in my experience in that you can
elevate the handlebars enough to sit in
a comfortable position with a decent
saddle, meaning the seat, such that I
can do the V2 and the V4 and all of that
training
>> Mhm.
>> for me in a comfortable position without
compromising my low back, which has been
a huge step forward. So this is the only
bike that I've used consistently for
this kind of training. And I was having
a number of conversations with a
neuroscientist named Dr. Tommy Wood over
a period of weeks. And if for instance,
you do something called the Norwegian 4
by 4, there's data to suggest that if
you do
it's VO2 max training. So it's very very
very intense, but it's like
>> Four on, four off.
>> Four minutes on, three to four minutes
off. Let's just call it three minutes.
Four minutes on, three minutes off. And
you do that for four rounds. This is the
only bike that I've been able to use
>> Mhm. to do this consistently. And if you
do that for I think it's three times a
week
for five to six months, the
volumetric changes, meaning the
neuroanatomical changes in the
hippocampus and other areas that are
certainly indicated in things like
Alzheimer's, lasts for up to five years.
>> Wow.
>> you do five to six months of gutting it
out three times a week,
>> Holy
>> get, the dividends pay off for it seems
up to or possibly beyond five years.
>> Holy
>> Crazy. So, throw in some sauna in there
and you're like good to go.
>> why I'm doing Yeah, I'm doing all the
usual stuff, right? I'm doing the sauna
and
don't let perfect be the enemy of good,
you know what I mean? It's like, okay,
sure, you don't have 30 minutes to do
it, like do 10 minutes. Like, you can't
do a sauna, take a hot bath. Like,
figure it out.
>> You know what my good is that I like?
>> What's that?
>> It's not perfect, but it's good, which
is I go on my treadmill, I set it to
>> Yeah.
>> So, it's like not like crazy, but it's
not Yeah, I can still do
>> Yeah.
>> And I set it to only like 2.5 on the
walking.
>> Yeah.
>> And I'll
play Duolingo chess cuz they have chess
on there now for Duolingo. They teach
you chess. It's amazing. And you can
play friends and live people and all
that stuff and they do game replays and
like teach and I'm learning a ton.
>> Yeah.
>> And 30, 40 minutes go by and you're
drenched in sweat.
>> I know it's not high intensity.
>> Yeah.
>> And all the benefits on the the
cognitive side seem to be around like a
lot of high end hits.
>> Yeah, but who knows?
>> But, it's good, right?
>> It's doing something.
>> It's doing something, right? So, I've
really enjoyed that. Like, if you if you
just want something to both be like
learning and engaged and kind of like
having fun,
>> Yeah.
>> so you forget about the time. Do you
know what I'm talking about where it's
like you just like, oh wait, what time
is it? Oh I've been on for 37
minutes, I can get off now, you know?
Like
>> I I love that type of cardio.
>> Yeah, I mean for me, I mean this is this
is going to sound like maybe a step
down, but it it's like the older I get,
the more I realize
a little goes a long way. Like
yesterday, for instance, I had a bunch
of stuff stacked up and I won't bore
people with the commitments, but
I didn't really have any time to go to
the gym and it was my day to go to the
gym to do X Y and Z exercises. And I
went in and I did three sets. I was
literally in there for 5 minutes and I
left.
>> Mhm. But it's better than nothing.
>> Right. Totally.
>> Something is better than nothing.